

Get In Touch

hello@klemire.com www.klemire.com 904.562.9172

Address

1237 W Carmen Ave. Apt 2n Chicago, IL 60640

Technologies

- React
- GraphQL
- JavaScript
- Node.JS
- MySQL
- · Adobe XD
- Adobe Photoshop

Disciplines

- Web Development
- · Web Content Accessibility
- UI Wireframing & Design
- · React Consulting

Education

University of Central FloridaBA Web Design
Aug 2012 — July 2017

Web Developer

Kyle Lemire

Personal Profile

I'm a JavaScript web developer with over 5 years of professional experience eager to expand my skills and build a better, more accessible web. I'm looking for a company that believes accessible design is good design and I look forward to applying my skills to help that company succeed in their mission.

Experience

2020 - Present

Freelance Web Development & Consulting

- Designing and building websites and applications with React, NextJS, and GatsbyJS
- Expert consultancy with front-end web development teams, teaching them React and GatsbyJS.
- Leveraging headless CMS's to deliver modern single-page applications with client-editable content.

Feb — Nov 2020

Web Developer @ Alpine Home Air

- Used React, Redux, and Server-Side Rendering to develop the company's e-commerce platform.
- Learned new server-side programming skills on the job to help support the company's legacy codebase.
- Collaborated directly with the designer to solve creative problems.
- Pushed for accessibility compliance and trained the designer on best practices such as color contrast ratio and ARIA to help inform design decisions

Jul 2017 — Nov 2020

Web Developer @ Elyk Innovation

- Personally built and deployed over a dozen client websites.
- Designed and developed custom Wordpress themes from the ground up.
- Trained clients to maintain and update their content, and provided ongoing support.
- Learned to foster and maintain ongoing client relationships.